Data Engineer and Backend Developer

# SRINIDHI SRIDHARAN

No. 1 Ponniamman Koil Street, puzhuthivakkam Chennai, India - 600091 Phone: +91 98401 98626 Email: <a href="mailto:srinidhi.s96@gmail.com">srinidhi.s96@gmail.com</a>

Portfolio:





### **Professional Summary**

An Analytics consultant with 2+ years of experience and well versed in data engineering and backend development especially on Cloud platforms. Has a proven track in working in Analytics - Centre of Excellence and later moved on to become Data Engineer.

#### **Technical Skills**

Database Development - SQL, NoSQL
Python for Data Science - Pyspark, Pandas
Java, REST API- Nodejs, C++
Data Modelling, Data Wrangling, Web Scraping
Hadoop, Apache Spark, Kafka

Cloud Platform - AWS, CloudFoundry Development SAP HANA , SAP Predictive Analytics and BI Tools Statistics R basics, Excel VBA Docker, Jenkins CI, Linux

#### **Education**

2014-2017 Bachelor of engineering, computer science and engineering, Meenakshi Sundararajan Engineering College

- CGPA: 8.84. University Rank Holder (Rank 24 out of 16,499 candidates under Anna University, Rank 3 in Overall CS department in College)
- Endowment prize for best academic performance, recognition for consistent performance in Semesters by Department of Mathematics.
- Student Lecturer, Member of NSS, College Choir, Overall coordinator for technical events in University culturals.

2011-2013 HIGHER SECONDARY - D.A.V HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL, MAJOR IN COMPUTER SCIENCE Secured 97% and a cash prize for best academic performance

1999-2011 CLASS X - HINDU SENIOR SECONDARY SCHOOL

- 10 CGPA. Present in Roll of Honour
- Multiple awards as vocalist in inter school culturals

## **Professional Experience**

Apr 2019 - May 2019

FREELANCER, - PAVO AND TUSKER INNOVATIONS\*

ML PLATFORM DEVELOPMENT, ML ENGINEER

- ML Engineer. Built and deployed a Spark engine that groups, filters and sort the data converted to pyspark dataframe
- Automated the process of data preparation, visualization based on cross validation techniques after fitting

into model

- Interactive tool for Data Scientists to load data, choose models and visualize the prediction results using binning.
- Algorithms Supported in Engine during Beta stage SVM Classifier, Logistic regression, Linear Regression, K-means clustering.

Aug 2018 - JULY 2019

ASSOCIATE CONSULTANT, DATA ENGINEERING - KAAR TECHNOLOGIES\*

PORTAL APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT - WORLDWIDE S/4HANA INNOVATION REQUEST REPOSITORY - BACKEND DEVELOPER, SAP CLOUD PLATFORM

CLIENT: SAP LABS - WALLDORF, GERMANY

- Built a complete Product Portfolio management tool for SAP S/4HANA cloud Team in SAP Walldorf with a team of only 2 developers and brought a profit margin of 80%.
- Lead the Project on requirement gathering, managed Sprint Deliverables, Improved their S/4HANA Innovation progress cycle by two fold.
- Responsible for Backend SQL and REST API development using SAP HANA Database, Nodejs, Python and SAP Analytics Cloud
- Early Adopter of New Cloud Foundry based Cloud Platform

OCT 2017 - JULY 2018

Analytics and integration consultant, center of excellence - Kaar technologies

REVAMPING THE REPORTING LANDSCAPE TO IN MEMORY COLUMNAR DATABASE WITH REAL TIME DATA INSIGHTS - BI CONSULTANT

JAN 2018 - FEB 2018, MAY 2018 - JULY 2018

CLIENTS: DAVID BROWN SANTASALO, UNITED KINGDOM
FIRST SOLAR INC, UNITED STATES
ZEKELMAN INDUSTRIES, UNITED STATES

- Revamped their traditional Reporting Landscape to SAP In-Memory Data platform that improves the data loading speed by 2.5x
- Interpreted their business KPIs and created data models from scratch
- Worked on SQL, multiple BI tools Tableau, MS Power BI, SAP Analytics Cloud, SAP Embedded analytics
- As an Integration consultant performed Integration in B2B scenarios between an On premise and a Cloud Platform Application using Cloud Platform Integration service built on top of Apache Camel Framework

## PROOF OF CONCEPTS PROJECT PROPOSAL:

\*Proof of Concepts are created as part of feasibility analysis of an idea or an approach from technology standpoint.

- ARCHITECTED THE SOLUTION AND IDENTIFIED THE PREDICTIVE MODELS FOR INDUSTRIAL INCIDENT PREDICTIONS (APR 2018)
  - Architected the Platform for Running Predictive models on HANA (In memory Data platform)
  - Identified the suitable models for Incident Severity Classification and Accident Prediction based on Parameters like Employee Training - Naive Bayes Model, Decision Tree Algorithms
- DEPLOYED ML ALGORITHMS FOR EXTENDED WARRANTY RATE PLANNING, PROOF OF CONCEPT, SAP PREDICTIVE ANALYTICS (MAR 2018)
  - o Pioneered the usage of **SAP Predictive Analytics** Library feature
  - Utilized the Pareto Analysis or ABC Model to identify the top 20% contributors to warranty Rate
- COMPETITIVE ANALYSIS OF PARTNERS WEB SCRAPING AND SEGMENTATION FOR MARKETING TEAM IN KAAR TECHNOLOGIES (DEC 2017)
  - Took initiative to Automate the data scraping process using Python for the marketing team by Setting up
     Web crawler to scrape the information on SAP partners which reduced their manpower cost

- Performed market segmentation on the scraped data that improved their sales pipeline for next 6 months
- HEALTHCARE KPI DASHBOARDS FOR MINISTRY OF HEALTH, KINGDOM OF SAUDI ARABIA (NOV 2017)
  - Created dashboard Prototypes for a \$10M+ Analytics proposal demo
  - Identified Key Performance Indicators for Healthcare and Diseases
  - o Provided Solution on Data Orchestration from 30+ External Sources

#### Internships

FEB 2017 SMART DATA INTEGRATION - CENTER OF EXCELLENCE, KAAR TECHNOLOGIES

- Proof of concept on Smart Data Integration Remote access of data from cloud and on premise systems and visualizing it on In memory columnar Database - HANA
- Comparative analysis between Smart Data Integration and SAP Cloud Platform Integration which is another Data Integration service.
- Monitored and handled the Application and platform lifecycle management.

MAY 2016 PARALLEL PROCESSING USING HADOOP AND MAPREDUCE - BIG DATA DEVELOPER, KRISH IT

- Setting up hadoop clusters and Working with unstructured Big data using Hadoop, Map Reduce in Python
- Performed Linguistic frequency generation and Social Network Graph analysis using Hadoop MapReduce

## **Projects**

STREAMING DATA PIPELINE FOR SENTIMENT ANALYSIS USING APACHE SPARK AND KAFKA

PIPELINE TO STORE SCRAPED DATA IN MONGODB USING PYTHON

RUNNING CENTRALITY ALGORITHMS ON SOCIAL GRAPH USING PYSPARK AND NEO4J (IN PROGRESS)

#### **Volunteer Experience**

Ex-Committee member and computer science tutor - SYMA , triplicane, Chennai

- Introduced the Computer Science Subject in their Growth System for Education and served as CS tutor for a vear
- Hosted events , Digitized their charity activities

NATIONAL SERVICE SCHEME MEMBER , MEENAKSHI SUNDARARAJAN ENGINEERING COLLEGE

Spearheaded the Swachh bharat initiative inside my college, attended service camps in poverty stricken area.

VOLUNTEER, PYCON INDIA 2019

MEMBER , TOASTMASTERS CLUB

# **Awards and Recognition**

PANEL'S CHOICE - ONE DAY HACKATHON, ANGEL HACK

Responsiblee - A Hyper-local application that provides credit scores to citizens based on their community participation. Played my part as Backend NOSQL developer using NoSQL Database - MongoDB.

MEMBER OF NASSCOM WOMEN WIZARD'S RULE TECH (W2RT)

Represented my company in NASSCOM's Initiative that focuses on grooming Women Technologists to turn into Leader by exposing us to Latest Technologies - Big Data, AI, VR, Cloud Computing, Block chain, 3D Printing through AI powered resource engine.

ACADEMIC EXCELLENCE, MEENAKSHI SUNDARARAJAN COLLEGE

Awarded Silver medal as Endowment Prize for Academic Excellence in 4th,5th and 7th semesters

BEST SINGER - ANNA UNIVERSITY, GUINDY

Emerged as the best singer in the intercollegiate music competition for NSS volunteers

MEMBER IN THE BOARD (2017 - 2018)- NGO, SYMA

Unanimously Elected as a committee member for serving in NGO in multiple roles for a year

DATA SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING EVANGELIST - KAAR TECH OMEGA INITIATIVE

<u>Data Science Evangelist</u>\* in Kaar Tech's Initiative for technological adoption into the company. Chosen based on my initiatives taken within the company for Improving their exposure to Data Science and Engineering

Received Star of the Month award twice

#### **Courses and Certification**

TAMING BIG DATA WITH MAP REDUCE AND HADOOP - LEARNING MAP REDUCE JOBS USING MRJOB - UDEMY

DIPLOMA IN COMPUTER APPLICATION - CSC COMPUTER EDUCATION

ARCHITECTING BIG DATA APPLICATIONS REAL-TIME APPLICATION ENGINEERING

MACHINE LEARNING BY ANDREW NG, STANFORD UNIVERSITY - COURSERA (UNDERGOING)

### **Language Skills**

тамі - Native Speaker

ENGLISH. Proficient in Writing, Reading, Speaking and Understanding.

FRENCH - Basic level in Reading, Speaking and Understanding.

## Reference

- 1. Vaidehi Srinivasan Solution Architect, Kaar Technologies
- 2. Monica Jeniffer Head of the Department, Computer Science, Meenakshi Sundararajan Engineering College
- 3. Sriram Subramanian CEO and Founder, Pavo & Tusker Innovations